让我们看看另一种请求
let's look at a different kind of request
创建新事物的帖子请求
a post request for creating new things
也许是新熊或任何其他新资源
maybe new bears or any other new resource
现在处理一个发布请求
now to handle a post request
我们必须考虑请求标头
we have to take into account the request headers
以及发布的参数
as well as the posted parameters
事实证明这是一个很好的遍历示例
and this turns out to be a neat example of traversing
和处理清单
and processing lists
我们将看到一种新型的模式匹配
we'll see a new type of pattern match and
甚至有点递归
even a bit of recursion
最后
and in the end
你将能够做出正面和反面
you'll be able to make heads and tails of it
我们已经让发布请求升温了
we already have the post request heat up down
在处理程序中
here in handler
所以方法是post
so the method is post
然后我们只是发布斜线熊
and then we're just posting the slash bears
当表格发布时
and when the form is posted
表单内容在 post 请求正文中编码
the form content is encoded in the post request body
这是最后一个
which is this last
就在这里线
line right here
你会看到它只是一组名称值对
and you see that it's just a set of name value pairs
用 &amp; 号分隔
separated by an ampersand
然后将名称与值分开
and then the names are separated from the values by
等号
an equal sign
我们有一个路由功能的起点
and we have a starting point for the route function
已经定义
already defined
因为这里没有什么新东西要学
since there's nothing new to learn here
我已经粘贴了最后一个
and I've pasted the last
请求的行在这里作为评论
line of the request up here as a comment
只是为了让我们记住它的样子
just so we remember what it looks like
我们的目标是解析请求的最后一行
our goal here is to parse the last line of the request
进入一个看起来像这样的参数地图
into a param's map that looks like this
是的，我们只有
yeah we'll just have
键与此处的键匹配
the keys match up with the keys here
并且值与值匹配
and the values match up with the values
所以这只是一张地图
so this is just a map
表示这个 post prim 字符串
that represents this post prim string
然后我们可以访问地图中的值
we can then access the values in the map
并在响应正文中使用它们
and use them in the response body
发音像
to pronounce something like
创建了一个无论熊的类型是什么
created a whatever the bear type is
以熊的名字命名
named the bear's name
显然这
obviously this
有效，因为 para 现在是硬涂层
works because the para are hard coated for now
所以我们需要让它动态化
so we're going to need to make it dynamic
现在我们知道这实际上并没有创建
now we know this doesn't actually create
数据库中的熊
a bear in the database
我们明白了，你可以
we get it you could
实际上做任何你想做的事
actually do whatever you want
此时有一只熊
with a bear at this point
但这现在超出了我们的范围
but that's sort of outside of our scope right now
我们将保持专注
we're going to stay focused instead
关于我们的网络服务器一般如何处理发布请求
on how our web server handles post request in general
所以让我们回顾一下
so let's look back
结束了我们如何解析请求
over at how we're parsing the request
在解析器中结束
over in parser
我们这里有解析函数
we have the parse function here
我们正在接受请求
and we're taking the request
我们正在拆分请求行
and we're splitting the request lines
然后我们只是解析第一个
and then we're just parsing the first
请求行
line which is the request line
好吧，让我们再看看我们的 post 请求
well let's look at our post request again
在处理程序结束
over in handler
好吧，这里是请求行
well here's the request line right here
我们在我们的部分函数中解析它
which we're parsing at our parts function
但我们还需要解析请求的最后一行
but we also need to parse the last line of the request
这是请求正文
this is the request body
这样我们就可以创建该参数的地图
so that we can create that param's map
所以这样做的一种方法是
so one way to do this would be to
在行中拆分请求
split the request in the lines
然后最后使用列表
and then use list at last
得到最后一行的身体
to get that last line the body
但提前考虑
but thinking ahead
我们最终想要重组请求
we ultimately want to restructure the request
分成我们可以工作的三个部分
into three parts that we can work
请求行是一个字符串
with the request line which is a string
身体是一串para
the body which is a string of para
然后是标题行
and then the header lines
因为这里的内容类型
because this content type here
会影响
will impact
我们如何最终在下一个模块中分割 para
how we ultimately parts the para in the next module
所以我们将首先拆分前两个
so we'll start by splitting the top two
参数字符串中的部分
parts from the param string
这很容易做到，因为有两个连续的
and that's easy to do because there's two consecutive
在这里和这里结束字符
end characters right here and here
所以回去吧，让我们继续做吧
so back over and parer let's go ahead and do that
我们将使用字符串拆分
we'll use string split
我们将接受整个请求
we're going to take the whole request
我们要把它分开
and we're going to split it
在双新线上
on a double new line
这将返回一个
and that's going to return a
包含两个元素的列表，以便我们可以对其进行模式匹配
list with two elements so we can pattern match on it
第一个元素是标题中的请求行
the first element is the request line in the headers
我将把它放入一个名为 top 的变量中
which I'm just going to put in a variable called top
然后
and then the
第二个元素将是我们的 prem 字符串
second element is going to be our prem string
这是请求的最后一行
that's the last line of the request
所以现在我们有了舞会字符串
so now we have the prom string
这就是我们的目标
which is what we were aiming for
但是我们丢失了我们的请求行，而我们可以取回它
but we lost our request line while we can get it back
通过拆分顶部而不是请求
by splitting top rather than request
是的，在这里我们将只使用顶部
yeah right here we'll just use top
然后我们要把它分成几行
and then we're going to split it into its lines
这将是请求
that's going to be the request
行和标题行
lines and the header lines
但我们只关心第一个
but we only care about the first one
我们拆分它以获得各个部分
and we split it to get the individual parts
方法路径和
the method the path and
我们不关心的协议
the protocol which we don't care about
如果我们把它保存起来
if we save that away
我们运行它
and we run it
它仍然有效，所以我们没有破坏任何东西
and it still works so we haven't broken anything
但这就是问题所在
but here's the problem
回看帖子请求
looking back at the post request
我们知道我们正在解析这一行
we know we're parsing this line
但我们需要这些剩余的行
but we need these remaining lines
标题行在他们自己的列表中
the header lines to be in a list of their own
这样我们就可以处理三个不同的部分
so that we have three distinct parts to work with
事实证明
and it turns out
我们可以编写一个模式来匹配请求行
we can write a pattern to match a request line
后跟任意数量的标题行
followed by any number of header lines
展示我们将如何做到这一点
to demonstrate how we're going to do that
让我们来玩一个简单的六位数的列表
let's play around with a simple list of numbers in six
现在我们知道我们可以匹配和破坏列表
now we know that we can match and destruct the list
通过在左侧放置一个图案
by putting a pattern on the left hand side
所以如果麻木在右手边
so if numbs is on the right hand side
我们的模式看起来像这样
our pattern is going to look like this
假设我们想在变量 ABCD 中捕获这些
let's say we want to capture these in variables ABCD
和 e
and e
那么 a 的值是一个值 b 将是两个
well the value of a is one value b is going to be two
一直到 e 的值为 5
all the way through to e which has a value of five
但假设我们想要第一个
but suppose we want the first
列表的元素是一个值
element of the list to be a value
然后剩下的元素是一个列表
and then the remaining elements to be a list
一个列表有一个头和一个尾
well a list has a head and a tail
我们可以通过模式匹配提取
which we can extract through pattern matching
使用称为 cons 运算符的东西
using something called the cons operator
看起来像这样，这是图案头竖条
it looks like this here's the pattern head vertical bar
尾巴
tail
然后右边我们有我们的数字列表
and then the right hand side we have our numbers list
现在如果我们看一下 head 的值，它是一个
now if we look at the value of head it's one the
tail 的值是一个列表
value of tail is a list
值为 2 到 5
with the values two through five
那么接下来如果尾部是一个列表本身
so what follows then that if the tail is a list itself
然后它也有头和尾
then it has a head and a tail as well
这意味着我们可以使用相同的模式匹配
which means we can use the same pattern match
所以如果我回到这里
so if I just go back up here
把尾巴放在右手边
and put tail on the right hand side
那么现在 head 的值是两个
well now the value of head is two
tail 的值是一个列表三四和五
the value of tail is a list three four and five
命名头发没有魔法
there's no magic to the naming hair
事实上 head 和 tail 通常缩写为 h 和 t
in fact head and tail are often abbreviated as h and t
分别是 cons 运算符竖线
respectively the cons operator the vertical bar
这是特制的酱汁
here it's the special sauce
所以让我们继续遍历这个列表
so let's go ahead and continue traversing the list this
大大地
way
现在 head 的值为 3
now the value of head is three
尾巴是四五
tail is four and five
现在领导四个
now heads four
而tail是单个元素列表五
and tail is a single element list five
现在这就是事情变得有趣的地方
now here's where things get interesting
现在头部是值 5
now the head is the value five
并且尾部是一个空列表
and the tail is an empty list
所以任何列表的最后一个元素的尾部是
so the tail of the final element of any list is
总是一个空列表
always an empty list
所以现在如果我们这样做会发生什么
so now what happens if we do this
好吧，那是不匹配的，因为尾巴
well that's not going to match because tail
是一个空列表
is an empty list
这与头部和尾部不匹配
and that doesn't match a head and a tail
所以列表要么是空的
so a list is either empty
或者它由头和尾组成
or it consists of a head and a tail
而尾部本身就是一个可以为空的列表
and the tail is itself a list which could be empty
我们已经看到了如何递归地遍历一个列表
and we've seen how we can traverse a list recursively
现在我们将回到这个递归
now we'll come back to this recursive
稍后再分开
part a little bit later
回到我们的帖子请求
coming back to our post request
目前
for now
我们想写一个模式来给我们这个请求
we want to write a pattern that gives us this request
行，然后将这些标题行作为列表提供给我们
line and then gives us these header lines as a list
所以这将是头
so this is going to be the head
这将是尾巴
and this is going to be the tail
所以让我们回到我们的解析器
so let's go back over to our parser
所以请记住，标题中的请求行在
so remember that the request line in the headers are in
最佳
top
所以一旦我们有顶部
so once we have the top
我们要把它分开
we're going to split it
刚刚上线
just on new lines
现在这将返回一个列表
now that's going to return a list
所以我们想要在这里进行模式匹配
so we want a pattern match over here
这给了我们头部和尾部
that gives us the head and the tail
好吧，头部是请求行
well the head is the request line
所以我们将放入一个可变的请求行
so we'll put in a variable request line
使用我们的竖线
use our vertical bar
然后是我们想要的标题行的尾部
and then the tail we want header lines
然后我们可以改变我们解析请求行的方式
then we can change how we parse the request line
分为三个部分
into its three parts
而不是这样做
instead of doing it this way
我们可以稍微简化一下
we can simplify this quite a bit
我们只是在请求行上说字符串拆分
we just say string split on the request line
我们用空格分开
and we split that by a space
获取该请求行的三个部分
to get the three parts of that request line
把它存起来
save that away
现在回到 ix 如果我们重新编译它
now back over an ix if we recompile that
好吧，看起来我们没有破坏任何东西
well it looks like we haven't broken anything
但我们有一个好处是请求破坏
but we have the bonus of having the request destruct
分为三个部分
into three parts
所以现在我们需要解析参数字符串
so now we need to parse the param string
所以我们动态地得到熊的名字和类型
so we get the name and the type of the bear dynamically
好吧，没有必要重新发明轮子
well there's no need to reinvent the wheel
这里
here
elixir 具有解码此查询字符串的功能
elixir has a function for decoding this query string
在 uri 模块中
in the uri module
有一个叫做解码查询的函数
there's a function called decode query
然后我在这里得到了查询字符串
and then I've got the query string right here
这是我们请求的最后一行
that's the last line of our request
这个功能的好处是
and what's great about this function is
它返回一张地图
it returns a map
键和值在哪里
where the keys and the values
与查询字符串中的内容相同
are the same thing that are in the query string
现在您可能很想将
now you might be tempted to convert the
字符串中的键
keys from strings
对原子和
to atoms and
使用原子作为键通常是一个不错的主意
using atoms as keys is generally a pretty good idea
但是在这种情况下很危险
however in this case it's dangerous
因为这些
because these
字符串来自我们的应用程序之外
strings are coming from outside of our application
而且由于原子不是在长生不老药中收集的垃圾
and since atoms aren't garbage collected in elixir
如果我们将它们转换为原子
if we convert them to atoms
好吧，我们可能会耗尽内存
well we can run out of memory
现在回到我们的解析器
now back over in our parser
我们可以定义一个函数
we can define a function
这将解码这个参数字符串
that will decode this param string
只是把它放在这里
just going to put it right down here
我称它为 parse para
and I'll call it parse para
这将包含我们的参数字符串
that's going to take in our param string
我将在这里使用管道
and I'm just going to use a pipeline here
该参数字符串的末尾有一个新行
there's a new line at the end of that param string
所以我想把它剪掉
so I want to trim that off
我将使用字符串修剪来做到这一点
I'll use string trim to do that
然后我们可以使用我们在 ix uri 中使用的那个函数
and then we can use that function we used in ix uri
解码查询
decode query
请记住，这将返回 para 的地图
and remember this is going to return a map of the para
然后在pars
and then up here in pars
我们将调用该函数
we'll call that function
我们将把结果分配给
and we're going to assign the result to
一个名为 paras 的变量
a variable called paras
只是会被解析 para
just going to be parsed para
并传入那个婴儿车字符串
and passing in that pram string
那么一旦我们有了婴儿车，我们就想要婴儿车地图
then once we have the prams we want the prams map
成为谈话的一部分
to be part of the conversation
所以我们将在这里添加一种感觉
so we'll just add a feel down here prams
并将其设置为该变量
and set it to that variable
所以让我们把它存起来试试看
so let's save that away and give it a try
我们将重新编译我们的应用程序
we'll recompile our application
哦，我们收到了一条空中信息
ooh and we get an air message
据说在调查中没有找到关键参数
it's saying the key paras was not found in survey
com 记住为
com which remembers a s
当一个计划一起出现时，你不只是喜欢它吗
don't you just love it when a plan comes together
是的，我们建立了这个结构来获得
yeah we set up this structure to get
类型安全，这正是它给我们的
type safety and that's exactly what it gave us
我们需要在被击中添加一个字段
we need to add a field to the struck
所以我要把这些放在不同的行上
so I'm going to put these on separate lines
然后我们将添加字段 paras
and then we'll add the field paras
我们将默认它只是一个空地图
and we're going to default it just to an empty map
现在让我们看看如果我们保存它会发生什么
now let's see what happens if we save that
重新编译
away in recompile
所以事实证明我们得到了另一个错误
so it turns out we get another error
但这与我们的代码无关
but it doesn't have to do with our code
看起来重新编译只是没有接受更改
it looks like recompile just didn't pick up the change
所以我重新启动了 ix，现在一切都在运行
so I restarted ix and everything's now running
我们看到我们的记录器输出中有婴儿车
and we see that we have the prams in our logger output
所以现在我们只需要使用这些
so now we just need to use these
我们的路线功能中的婴儿车
prams in our route function
回到我们的处理程序模块
that's back over in our handler module
我们这里有这款硬涂层婴儿车
and we have this hard coated prams right here
好吧，我们不再需要那个了
well we don't need that anymore
相反，我们可以使用
instead we can just use
来
come
点参数，因为这是我们添加的新字段
dot params because that's the new field that we added
同样的事情就在这里
and the same thing right here
把它存起来
save that away
现在如果我们重新编译它
and now if we recompile this
果然我们得到了一只名叫球的棕熊
well sure enough we get created a brown bear named ball
所以我们的 para 不再是硬涂层
so our para are no longer hard coated
但是我们这样做的方式有点冒昧
but the way we did this it's a bit presumptuous
我们将在下一节中了解原因
and we'll see why in the next section